the spookiest math curve is the infamous
Witch of anessi originally named by
Maria anessi the first woman appointed
to the math professor it was then later
completely mistranslated to woman who is
against God and then to which now we can
construct it geometrically by starting
with the circle of radius a then taking
a point on the circle and drawing the
segment from the origin out to the point
P if you put a horizontal tangent at the
top of the circle and extend our segment
out until it intersects with that
horizontal finally drop it de down until
it matches the height of the point P
this gives us a new Point as we move
around the circle you sketch out a curve
this is the witch of anessi analytically
this curve is given by 8 a cub / x^2 + 4
a^ 2 where a is the radius of the circle
and I'm a particular fan of the special
case where a is equal to 12 and in this
case it simplifies to just be 1x^2 + 1
now any good mathemagician can make Pi
appear so let's integrate from 0 to 1
and the calculus students among you will
recognize that this is the derivative of
arctan and so evaluating at 0 and 1
gives the value of pi over 4 but if
instead we had looked at the inside and
expanded using geometric series to give
1 - x^2 + X4 - x 6 and so on then
integrate term by term evaluated at the
zero and the one and you get the series
1 - 1/3 plus 5th - 17th and so forth
this is a series expansion for pi